A Guide to the Lincoln Chen papers FA1279
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lincoln Chen papers
1995-2003
Rockefeller Archive Center
Chen, Lincoln C.
Rockefeller Foundation
Harvard University. Global Equity Initiative
FA1279
3.42 Cubic Feet 9 letter-size document boxes
Scope and Contents
This collection documents various conferences, meetings, and workshops attended by Lincoln Chen, both during his tenure at the Rockefeller Foundation and at the Global Equity Initiative. The files include agendas, participant lists, articles and pre-readings, promotional information, and notes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Lincoln Chen is an expert on international public health. He graduated from Princeton University (BA), Harvard Medical School (MD), and the Johns Hopkins School of Hygiene and Public Health (MPH). In 1973, Dr. Chen joined the Ford Foundation, serving in Bangladesh and India. From 1987 to 1996, he served as Taro Takemi Professor of International Health at the Harvard School of Public Health as well as Director of the University-wide Harvard Center for Population and Development Studies. He then joined the Rockefeller Foundation as Executive Vice President for Strategy. In 2001, he founded the Global Equity Initiative at the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University. He was Director of the Initiative from 2001 to 2006. Dr. Chen is currently the President of the China Medical Board.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was received from Lincoln Chen in two shipments in 2009.
- Ad Hoc Board Strategy Committee, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Rockefeller Foundation Ad Hoc Board Strategy Committee
- "The Art of Double Bottom Line Investing," Rockefeller Foundation and the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, 2000 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brazil, South Africa, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  "Beyond Racism: Embracing an Interdependent Future" (4 reports)
- Building Strategic Partnerships in Education and Health in Africa, 2002 January 28-February 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Consultative Meeting on Improving Collaboration between Health Professionals, Governments, and Other Stakeholders in Human Resources for Health Development, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
- Conference on Efficient Equity Oriented Strategies for Health in Vietnam, 1999 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Consultation on International Migration, Berlin, 2002 October 22-23 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  The Global Equity Initiative
- Enhancing World Health Institutions, Pocantico/Bellagio, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Pocantico Meeting: Enhancing the Performance of International Health Institutions
- Fourth Intellectual Dialogue on Building Asia's Tomorrow, 2002 March 16-17 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Future Directions in Health, Background Readings, Bellagio, 1997 April 1-5 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- "Global Philanthropy: Where Are We? Where Do We Want to Go? How Do We Get There?", 2001 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Meeting, Rockefeller Foundation
- Health and Human Security Workshop, 2002 October 15-16 (Box 3, Box 12)
  The Global Equity Initiative, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University
- Health Equity Division Retreat, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  Health Equity Division of the Rockefeller Foundation
- Health Sciences Planning Meeting, Rockefeller Foundation, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1997 May 8-9 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Human Security, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Human Security, Memos, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Human Security Research Seminar, Readings, 1995 Spring (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
- Meeting on AIDS in Africa, 2001 April (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Convened by the Rockefeller Foundation, Hosted by The Joint Clinical Research Centre and Makerere University, Co-sponsored by the Joint United Nations Program on AIDS (UNAIDS), the United States National Institutes of Health (NIH), and the Global Forum for Health Research (GFHR)
- MIHR/Bellagio Meeting, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Management of Intellectual Property Rights for Health Research and Development, Improved Management of IPR during R&D of Health Products, Management of IP in Health R&D
  - The Rockefeller Foundation Meeting on Management of IP in Health R&D, MIHR, Selected Documents, Bellagio, 2001 November 5-8; 2017:FA1279:001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Nonprofit Sector Data Infrastructure Funders Meeting, 2001 July 24 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Meeting held at The Ford Foundation
- Pan American Health in the 21st Century: Strengthening of International Cooperation and Human Resources Development, 1997-2003 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  Public Health in the 21st Century; Cancun
- Philanthropy, Global, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Philanthropy, Health, and Human Security, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Includes: Global Philanthropy Forum: Borderless Giving, Conference Global Social Investing: A Preliminary Overview Advancing Stability in an Era of Change: Project on World Security, Rockefeller Brothers Fund "Human Security: Opportunities for Global Health?" by Chen and Narasimhan Cairo Statement on Health and Human Security Globalization and Human Security, Weatherhead Policy Forum "Why Human Security?" by Sen Notes from Dinner Remarks by David de Ferranti at Cambridge, Mass. "Philanthropy and Social Change in Latin America: Strategies and Lessons" by Chen "Future of Philanthropy: Philanthropy for Global Equity" by Chen "Mexico and the Rockefeller Foundation: Future Collaboration in Public Health" by Chen Philanthropy and Social Change in Latin America: Strategies and Lessons, A Workshop for Donors and Practitioners "Educational Inequality and Philanthropy in Latin America. Opportunities for Leadership" by Reimers
- Philanthropy, Incubator, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Philanthropy, One World Foundation, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Philanthropy, ProVenEx/Biosyn/World2Market, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Rockefeller Foundation, Program Venture Experiment
- RF Hewlett Social Investing, "Social Intent and Returns: An Exploration of Investors, Instruments, and the Pursuit of a Social Return on Investment", 2001 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Rockefeller Foundation, William and Flora Hewlett Foundation
- RF in China, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 31, Box 6, Folder 32)
  "An overview of our long involvement with projects in China"
- RF Theme/Cross-Theme Strategy Papers, 2000 June 5-9 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Statistics and Data Collection, Informal Economy, Geneva, 2002 May-July (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
- Strategy Policy Literature: Annual Reports: "Good as Gold: Preserving Community Resources in Nonprofit Conversions", 2000 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  Vc
- Strategy Policy Literature: Foundation Strategies, 1997-2000 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  Va
- Strategy Policy Literature: Organizational Learning, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  Vb; Organizational Learning - Thought Paper
- Technology: Biotechnology for Food, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  IIIB
- Technology: Biotechnology for Health, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  IIIC
- Technology: Information Technology, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  IIIA
- Technology: UNDP/HDR, Human Development Report, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  IIID
- Technology Literature: Health, 1996-2000 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  IIIc
- Technology Literature: Information Technology, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  IIIb
- Technology Literature: Mastering the Machine, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  IIId
- Technology Literature: News Articles, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  IIIa
- T.N. Krishnan Memorial Symposium, "Social Sector Strategies and Financing for Human Development in India", 1997 April 24-25 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  Sponsored by the Harvard Center for Population and Development Studies and the United Nations Development Programme/India
- UNDP/HDR, Human Development Report, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 48-49)
- WHO Conference on Biotechnology and Genomics for Improvement of Health in Developing Countries, Havana, Cuba, 2002 March 25-27 (Box 8, Folder 50)
- Workshop, Barker-Marmont, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- Workshop on Comparative Global Philanthropy, Harvard University, 2002 September 18-20 (Box 8, Folder 52)
- Workshop on New Insecurities, 2002 October 29-30 (Box 8, Folder 53)
- Workshop RF NYC, Second Bellagio Program Retreat for Field Staff, 1999 June 14-17 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  Also includes "Outline: RF Latin American Programs"
- Workshop, U.S.-Mexico Border Health Commission, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 55)
- Workshops and Meetings, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  Includes: Philanthropy Workshop, 2002 November Meeting on Safety and Security in Education, 2002 November 7 Future Challenges Facing the WHO, 2002 November 10-11 The Fifth Intellectual Dialogue on Building Asia's Tomorrow - Bangkok Workshop, 2002 December 12
- World Academy of Art and Science, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 57)